<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>J. de Rossi Molina</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>J. de Rossi Molina</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    
      
        <managingEditor>jeronimo@derossimolina.com.br
          
            (J. de Rossi Molina)
          
        </managingEditor>
      

      
    

    
    <copyright>© 2024 J. de Rossi Molina</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>History of Python</title>
      <link>/garden/python_history/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jeronimo@derossimolina.com.br (J. de Rossi Molina)</author>
      <guid>/garden/python_history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Python was created in the late 1980s, a time when most programming languages were complex and aimed at computing professionals. Guido van Rossum, the Dutch programmer behind its creation, wanted to develop a programming language that was simple and easy to learn. His goal was to make programming accessible to more people without requiring deep technical knowledge. Thus, Python was born with the promise of being &amp;ldquo;easy to read and write.&amp;rdquo; And why the name Python? Van Rossum was a fan of the British comedy group &amp;ldquo;Monty Python’s Flying Circus&amp;rdquo; and decided to name the language in their honor, bringing a sense of lightness and simplicity—qualities that have come to define the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand the importance of this milestone, it’s worth recalling that programming at the time was seen as a technical and dry domain. Languages like C, for instance, required extensive knowledge of specific details, with a steep learning curve that deterred most outside the technical fields. Python challenged this tradition by aiming to make programming accessible to everyone, including those without a technical background—and in this, it succeeded brilliantly. From the outset, Python prioritized code clarity and readability, lowering the barrier for new programmers, particularly from fields like the Humanities, who work with data but for whom programming is not a central focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;syntax&#34; &gt;
&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#syntax&#34;&gt;
        #
    &lt;/a&gt;
    Syntax
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python features a direct and concise syntax: it requires fewer punctuation marks and complex commands, making the code shorter and easier to read. For those in the Humanities, this makes all the difference, enabling tasks that were previously difficult and time-consuming to be completed quickly and without many obstacles. This simplicity is one of the factors that made Python a popular choice among professionals and researchers in History, Sociology, Economics, and even fields like Literature. Many of these professionals have found Python to be a valuable tool for analyzing textual data, conducting quantitative research, and exploring new methods of analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jeronimo@derossimolina.com.br (J. de Rossi Molina)</author>
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
